ALESSANDRO ARRIGO

Contact

Address:

Vicolo Valguarnera, 12 90133 Palermo, IT

Telephone:

(+39) 392 8057506

Email:

alessandro.arrigo.stat@gmail.com

Website:

www.alearrigo.com

Skill Highlights

- Decision-oriented statistical analysis
- Data Modelling
- Data Mining
- Complex problem solver

Languages

Italian – Native English – C1

Technical Skills

Microsoft Office Database: SQL Statistical Analysis: R

Awards

"Stats under the Stars 2018"

1° prize in "Best results presentation" category and 2° prize in "Best predictive model" category.

Summary

Data Scientist with 2+ years of experience interpreting and analyzing data in order to drive successful business solutions. Proficient knowledge in statistics, mathematics, and analytics. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective analysis of data.

Professional Experiences

Freelance Statistical Consulting – From 07/2019 to Present Remote

 Provided research support (cleaning and analyzing data) for several projects spanned survey data and social networks data.
Worked with both private and institutional clients.

Co-founder e Analytics Lead – From 11/2017 to 05/2019 **Dexlab.io**, Berlin

- Identified market and product opportunities.
- Main focus on predictive models of bitcoin, ether and other cryptocurrencies's price and volatility.
- Done research on topics of cryptoeconomics, new blockchain protocols and their internal dynamics.

Techincal Translator – From 04/2018 to 07/2018 **Loopring Project Ltd,** Remote

 Wrote the Italian translation of Loopring's protocol whitepaper and several blog posts as part of international community building effort.

Education

Master's Degree: Statistics – 2019

Università degli Studi di Palermo. 110 cum laude/110

Thesis: "Modelling Bitcoin Volatility: A Markov Regime Switching GARCH Approach".

Bachelor's Degree : **Economics and Finance** – 2015

Università degli Studi di Palermo. 92/110

Thesis: "The role of Big Data in the evolution of Business Intelligence".